<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:snf="http://www.smartnews.be/snf" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>News - MyAnimeList</title>
    <description>MyAnimeList's Feed of News</description>
    <link>https://myanimelist.net/news?_location=rss</link>
    <item>
      <guid>https://myanimelist.net/news/67553378?_location=rss</guid>
      <title>'Itou Junji: Maniac' Unveils Main Staff, Additional Cast, January 19 Premiere</title>
      <description> The Netflix TUDUM Japan event revealed on Sunday the main staff and additional cast members for the Itou Junji: Maniac (Junji Ito Maniac: Japanese Tales of the Macabre) net anime series. The anime is scheduled to premiere worldwide on Netflix on January 19. Cast Tomie Tomie: Rie Suegara (Itou Junji: Collection) Tsukiko Izumisawa: Yumiri Hanamori (Yofukashi no Uta) Yamazaki: Taku Yashiro (Domestic na Kanojo) Taichi: Tomokazu Sugita (Gintama) Kimata: Hiroyuki Yoshino (Spy x Family) Shijuu Kabe no...</description>
      <media:thumbnail>https://cdn.myanimelist.net/s/common/uploaded_files/1664092688-dd34666e64d7ae624e6e2c70087c181f.jpeg</media:thumbnail>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Sep 2022 01:02:33 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://myanimelist.net/news/67553378?_location=rss</link>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid>https://myanimelist.net/news/67553325?_location=rss</guid>
      <title>'Make My Day' Reveals Main Cast, Additional Staff, February 2023 Premiere</title>
      <description> The Netflix TUDUM Japan event revealed the main cast and one additional staff for the original anime series Make My Day. The anime will premiere worldwide on Netflix in February 2023. Cast Jim: Masaomi Yamahashi (Rokudenashi Majutsu Koushi to Akashic Records) Marnie: Ayahi Takagaki (Senki Zesshou Symphogear) Walter: Kazuhiro Yamaji (Shingeki no Kyojin Season 3) Captain Burke: Akio Ootsuka (Koukaku Kidoutai) Kensuke Ushio (Devilman: Crybaby, Heike Monogatari) is composing the music. Manga author...</description>
      <media:thumbnail>https://cdn.myanimelist.net/s/common/uploaded_files/1664094149-7003a2d793adb3058043c4506fd847b1.jpeg</media:thumbnail>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Sep 2022 00:54:43 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://myanimelist.net/news/67553325?_location=rss</link>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid>https://myanimelist.net/news/67553252?_location=rss</guid>
      <title>Baku Yumemakura's 'Onmyouji' Novel Gets Anime in 2023</title>
      <description> An anime adaptation of Baku Yumemakura&#039;s Onmyouji novel series was announced at the Netflix TUDUM Japan event on Sunday, revealing the main staff, a concept art (pictured above), and a character visual for Abe no Seimei (pictured right). The anime series will debut worldwide on Netflix in 2023. Soubi Yamamoto (Meganebu!) is directing the anime at Marvy Jack. Natsu Hashimoto (Oshiete Hokusai! The Animation) and Yuiko Katou (Aguu: Tensai Ningyou) are penning the script. Yumemakura originally...</description>
      <media:thumbnail>https://cdn.myanimelist.net/s/common/uploaded_files/1664091670-da678a78a6b44fb0d1790f2fd8e7ce58.jpeg</media:thumbnail>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Sep 2022 00:42:10 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://myanimelist.net/news/67553252?_location=rss</link>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid>https://myanimelist.net/news/67552991?_location=rss</guid>
      <title>'Aggressive Retsuko' Gets Fifth Season in February 2023</title>
      <description> The Netflix TUDUM Japan event announced a fifth season of Sanrio&#039;s Aggressive Retsuko (Aggretsuko) net anime series on Sunday. The final season is scheduled to premiere worldwide on Netflix in February 2023. The first anime adaptation based on Sanrio&#039;s titular red panda mascot aired in 100 one-minute episodes from April 2016 to March 2018 on TBS&#039; Ousama no Brunch program. TBS subsequently combined all 100 episodes and broadcast them in 10 episodes. The first, second, third, and f...</description>
      <media:thumbnail>https://cdn.myanimelist.net/s/common/uploaded_files/1664087997-665c6083b3f270552be12d3f358e5fef.jpeg</media:thumbnail>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Sep 2022 23:41:49 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://myanimelist.net/news/67552991?_location=rss</link>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid>https://myanimelist.net/news/67552810?_location=rss</guid>
      <title>Video Game 'Onimusha' Gets Anime Series</title>
      <description> The Netflix TUDUM Japan event announced on Sunday an anime adaptation of Capcom&#039;s Onimusha video game series and revealed the main staff members. Staff Chief Director: Takashi Miike (Koroshiya 1 live-action director) Director: Shinya Sugai (Dragon&#039;s Dogma) Musashi Miyamoto Model: Toshirou Mifune (Yojimbo) Studio: Sublimation Capcom developed and published the first game in the series in January 2001 in Japan for Playstation 2 and released an updated version for Xbox in 2002. Onimusha...</description>
      <media:thumbnail>https://cdn.myanimelist.net/s/common/uploaded_files/1664086234-c75d1721efa9953b6ce0d13fc2060405.jpeg</media:thumbnail>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Sep 2022 23:12:07 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://myanimelist.net/news/67552810?_location=rss</link>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid>https://myanimelist.net/news/67552685?_location=rss</guid>
      <title>Manhwa 'Lookism' Gets Anime Series</title>
      <description> The Netflix TUDUM Japan event announced an anime adaptation of Tae-Jun Park&#039;s Lookism manhwa on Sunday, revealing a teaser visual (pictured above) and teaser promotional video. The anime series, produced by Studio Mir, with stream worldwide on Netflix under the title Gaiken Shijou Shugi on November 4. Park launched the action drama manhwa on the Naver Webtoon (now Line Webtoon) webcomic portal in November 2014. The 20th volume went on sale on May 20. LINE Webtoon began releasing the title...</description>
      <media:thumbnail>https://cdn.myanimelist.net/s/common/uploaded_files/1664085581-ae3c0cc36e1590533915844da315a386.jpeg</media:thumbnail>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Sep 2022 23:00:59 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://myanimelist.net/news/67552685?_location=rss</link>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid>https://myanimelist.net/news/67552429?_location=rss</guid>
      <title>'Gokushufudou' Gets 2nd Season for January 2023</title>
      <description>The Netflix TUDUM Japan event announced a second anime season for Kousuke Oono&#039;s Gokushufudou (The Way of the Househusband) manga on Sunday. The new season will stream worldwide on Netflix in January 2023. Chiaki Kon (Higurashi no Naku Koro ni, Nodame Cantabile: Paris-hen) is returning to direct the second season at J.C.Staff (Prison School, Amanchu!). Susumu Yamakawa (Back Street Girls: Gokudolls) is also returning to handle the series composition. The first season premiered in two five-ep...</description>
      <media:thumbnail>https://cdn.myanimelist.net/s/common/uploaded_files/1664083433-a3d4909cf423596844d7facd1868cd4f.jpeg</media:thumbnail>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Sep 2022 22:24:22 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://myanimelist.net/news/67552429?_location=rss</link>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid>https://myanimelist.net/news/67552354?_location=rss</guid>
      <title>'Moonrise' Reveals Additional Staff, Teaser Promo, 2024 Premiere</title>
      <description>The Netflix TUDUM Japan livestream event announced on Sunday additional staff, a teaser visual (pictured), and teaser promotional video for Wit Studio&#039;s Moonrise original anime series. The anime is scheduled to premiere worldwide on Netflix in 2024. Staff Original Creator: Tow Ubukata (Mardock Scramble) Original Character Design: Hiromu Arakawa (Fullmetal Alchemist) Director: Masashi Koizuka (Shingeki no Kyoujin Season 2) Character Design: Ayumi Yamada (Owari no Seraph sub-character design)...</description>
      <media:thumbnail>https://cdn.myanimelist.net/s/common/uploaded_files/1664082428-d9061ce414c539b87e7e326254038bb8.jpeg</media:thumbnail>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Sep 2022 22:07:59 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://myanimelist.net/news/67552354?_location=rss</link>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid>https://myanimelist.net/news/67547345?_location=rss</guid>
      <title>'Arknights: Reimei Zensou' Reveals Additional Staff, Cast, First Promo</title>
      <description>The official website of the Arknights: Reimei Zensou (Arknights Animation: Prelude to Dawn) television anime revealed additional staff, cast, opening theme, a promotional video and key visual (pictured) on Saturday. The anime is scheduled to broadcast on October 29 at 1:23 a.m. on TV Tokyo, followed by TV Osaka, BS11, and Animax. Cast Doctor: Yuki Kaida (Tennis no Ouji-sama) Amiya: Tomoyo Kurosawa (Hibike! Euphonium) Dobermann: Atsumi Tanezaki (Spy x Family) Nearl: Ayane Sakura (Boku no Hero Aca...</description>
      <media:thumbnail>https://cdn.myanimelist.net/s/common/uploaded_files/1664038361-4f428fd8e3555417e6744cd033534480.jpeg</media:thumbnail>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Sep 2022 10:05:22 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://myanimelist.net/news/67547345?_location=rss</link>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid>https://myanimelist.net/news/67544667?_location=rss</guid>
      <title>Sony Music Project 'UniteUp' Gets TV Anime in Winter 2023</title>
      <description>The Aniplex Online Fest 2022 event announced a television anime adaptation for Sony Music Entertainment Japan&#039;s UniteUp! project on Saturday, revealing the main cast and a teaser promotional video. Produced by CloverWorks, the anime series will broadcast in January 2023. Cast PROTOSTAR Akira Kiyose: Kikunosuke Toya (Chainsaw Man) Banri Naoe: Ryoutarou Yamaguchi (Futsal Boys!!!!!) Chihiro Isuzugawa: Amon Hirai LEGIT Daiki Takao: Magura Sukegawa Eishiro Nijo: Shinnosuke Morikage Fuga Togo: Ry...</description>
      <media:thumbnail>https://cdn.myanimelist.net/s/common/uploaded_files/1664017403-2196103af4549159b1d005e830d8ee00.jpeg</media:thumbnail>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Sep 2022 04:42:14 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://myanimelist.net/news/67544667?_location=rss</link>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid>https://myanimelist.net/news/67544062?_location=rss</guid>
      <title>'Ayakashi Triangle' TV Anime Main Cast Announced</title>
      <description>The Aniplex Online Fest 2022 event revealed the main cast and a second teaser visual (pictured) for the Ayakashi Triangle anime series on Saturday. The television anime adapting Kentarou Yabuki&#039;s ecchi comedy manga will premiere in January 2023. Cast Matsuri Kazamaki (Male): Shouya Chiba (Jibaku Shounen Hanako-kun) Matsuri Kazamaki (Female): Miyu Tomita (Ore dake Haireru Kakushi Dungeon) Suzu Kanade: Kana Ichinose (Hige wo Soru. Soshite Joshikousei wo Hirou.) Shirogane: Tesshou Genda (Oda C...</description>
      <media:thumbnail>https://cdn.myanimelist.net/s/common/uploaded_files/1664013608-b8ff9c9da3eb1c233d05167b9bab5480.jpeg</media:thumbnail>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Sep 2022 03:00:32 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://myanimelist.net/news/67544062?_location=rss</link>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid>https://myanimelist.net/news/67543892?_location=rss</guid>
      <title>Gen Urobuchi's 'Eisen Flügel' Light Novel Gets Anime Movie</title>
      <description>The Aniplex Online Fest 2022 event announced an anime movie adaptation of Gen Urobuchi&#039;s Eisen Fl&uuml;gel light novel on Saturday. Aniplex simultaneously launched an official website, revealing the production staff, a teaser promotional video, and teaser visual (pictured). Urobuchi penned the light novel in two volumes under Shogakukan&#039;s Gagaga Bunko label in July and December 2009, featuring illustrations by Higashiguchi Chuuou (Mnemosyne: Mnemosyne no Musume-tachi). Anno Nanakamado...</description>
      <media:thumbnail>https://cdn.myanimelist.net/s/common/uploaded_files/1664011728-03b143e16b1025a23577008fb207c634.jpeg</media:thumbnail>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Sep 2022 02:28:59 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://myanimelist.net/news/67543892?_location=rss</link>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid>https://myanimelist.net/news/67543736?_location=rss</guid>
      <title>'Seishun Buta Yarou' Anime Series Sequel Announced</title>
      <description> The Aniplex Online Fest 2022 event announced a sequel for the anime series adapting Hajime Kamoshida&#039;s Seishun Buta Yarou Series (Rascal Does Not Dream) light novel on Saturday. The event also revealed the main cast, staff, teaser visual (pictured), and an announcement promo. The new anime project will cover the eighth and ninth novel volumes titled Seishun Buta Yarou wa Odekake Sister no Yume wo Minai (Rascal Does Not Dream of a Sister Venturing Out) and Seishun Buta Yarou wa Randoseru Gi...</description>
      <media:thumbnail>https://cdn.myanimelist.net/s/common/uploaded_files/1664064362-eff108a231a521c9e0d749151c2cd517.jpeg</media:thumbnail>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Sep 2022 01:58:04 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://myanimelist.net/news/67543736?_location=rss</link>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid>https://myanimelist.net/news/67543640?_location=rss</guid>
      <title>Manga 'Yamada-kun to Lv999 no Koi wo Suru' Gets TV Anime in 2023</title>
      <description>The Aniplex Online Fest 2022 event announced on Saturday a television anime adaptation of Mashiro&#039;s Yamada-kun to Lv999 no Koi wo Suru (Loving Yamada at Lv999) manga and revealed the main cast, staff, teaser visual (pictured), and teaser promotional video. The anime is scheduled to premiere in 2023. Inori Minase (5-toubun no Hanayome) and Kouki Uchiyama (Horimiya) are starring as Akane Kinoshita and Akito Yamada, respectively. Staff Director: Morio Asaka (Chihayafuru) Series Composition: Ya...</description>
      <media:thumbnail>https://cdn.myanimelist.net/s/common/uploaded_files/1664008520-2488faf98f588082b192aa47738477e3.jpeg</media:thumbnail>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Sep 2022 01:35:58 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://myanimelist.net/news/67543640?_location=rss</link>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid>https://myanimelist.net/news/67543518?_location=rss</guid>
      <title>'Shiro Seijo to Kuro Bokushi' Unveils Main Cast, Additional Staff, Spring 2023 Premiere</title>
      <description>The Aniplex Online Fest 2022 event unveiled the main cast, additional staff, teaser visual (pictured), and a teaser promotional video for the television anime adaptation of Hazano Kazutake&#039;s Shiro Seijo to Kuro Bokushi (Saint Cecilia and Pastor Lawrence) manga on Saturday. The anime is scheduled to premiere in April 2023. Hime Sawada and Kaito Ishikawa (Seishun Buta Yarou wa Bunny Girl Senpai no Yume wo Minai) stars as Cecilia and Lawrence, respectively. Staff Art Director: Chieko Nakamura...</description>
      <media:thumbnail>https://cdn.myanimelist.net/s/common/uploaded_files/1664006632-b80c8ee3415c8893d4b0a10837a471bf.jpeg</media:thumbnail>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Sep 2022 01:05:06 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://myanimelist.net/news/67543518?_location=rss</link>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid>https://myanimelist.net/news/67543446?_location=rss</guid>
      <title>Light Novel 'Fate/strange Fake' Gets TV Special in December 2022</title>
      <description> The Aniplex Online Fest 2022 event announced a television special anime for Ryohgo Narita&#039;s Fate/strange Fake light novel on Saturday. Aniplex simultaneously opened an official website, revealing the main staff, cast, a teaser visual (pictured) and teaser promo. The special episode, subtitled Whispers of Dawn, will debut on December 31 this year. Staff Director: Shun Enokido (Manga de Wakaru! Fate/Grand Order), Takahito Sakazume (Princess Connect! Re:Dive Season 2 episode director) Script:...</description>
      <media:thumbnail>https://cdn.myanimelist.net/s/common/uploaded_files/1664005495-19c4a2d53da1a9d24c93d0ab4313639a.jpeg</media:thumbnail>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Sep 2022 00:45:55 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://myanimelist.net/news/67543446?_location=rss</link>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid>https://myanimelist.net/news/67543338?_location=rss</guid>
      <title>'Mashle' TV Anime Reveals Main Cast, Staff</title>
      <description>The Aniplex Online Fest 2022 event revealed main cast and staff for the Mashle television anime on Saturday. The anime is scheduled to premiere in 2023. Voice actor Chiaki Kobayashi (Tomodachi Game) is starring as Mash Burnedead. Staff Director: Tomoya Tanaka (Engage Kiss) Series Composition: Yousuke Kuroda (Boku no Hero Academia) Character Design: Hisashi Toujima (Sword Art Online: Progressive Movie prop design) Music: Masaru Yokoyama (Ao Ashi) Studio: A-1 Pictures Koumoto began serializing the...</description>
      <media:thumbnail>https://cdn.myanimelist.net/s/common/uploaded_files/1664004366-765deb5950555733aa5e75edb0ed3adb.jpeg</media:thumbnail>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Sep 2022 00:26:51 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://myanimelist.net/news/67543338?_location=rss</link>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid>https://myanimelist.net/news/67543111?_location=rss</guid>
      <title>'NieR:Automata' Reveals Main Cast, Staff for Winter 2023</title>
      <description>The Aniplex Online Fest 2022 event announced the main staff, cast, and a teaser promotional video for the NieR:Automata television anime series on Saturday. The anime is scheduled to premiere in January 2023. Yui Ishikawa (Shingeki no Kyojin) and Natsuki Hanae (Summertime Render) are reprising their roles from the game as YoRHa 2-gou B-gata and YoRHa 9-gou S-gata, respectively. Hiroki Yasumoto (ACCA: 13-ku Kansatsu-ka) and Kaoru Akiyama (Detective Conan) are also returning as Pod 042 and 153. St...</description>
      <media:thumbnail>https://cdn.myanimelist.net/s/common/uploaded_files/1664002401-72e4516f587d1484fd09a90518ec9a96.jpeg</media:thumbnail>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Sep 2022 23:54:28 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://myanimelist.net/news/67543111?_location=rss</link>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid>https://myanimelist.net/news/67542924?_location=rss</guid>
      <title>'Tomo-chan wa Onnanoko!' Announces Additional Cast Pair</title>
      <description>The Aniplex Online Fest 2022 event revealed two additional cast and a character introduction promo for the Tomo-chan wa Onnanoko! (Tomo-chan Is a Girl!) television anime on Saturday. The anime series adapting Fumita Yanagida&#039;s romantic comedy web manga will premiere in January 2023. Kouhei Amasaki (High Score Girl) and Yoshitsugu Matsuoka (5-toubun no Hanayome) are joining the cast as Kousuke Misaki and Tatsumi Tanabe, respectively. Hitoshi Nanba (Golden Kamuy) is directing the anime at Lay...</description>
      <media:thumbnail>https://cdn.myanimelist.net/s/common/uploaded_files/1664000449-9b35b85132e0d95e178cf26c3144e50a.jpeg</media:thumbnail>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Sep 2022 23:21:42 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://myanimelist.net/news/67542924?_location=rss</link>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid>https://myanimelist.net/news/67542620?_location=rss</guid>
      <title>New 'Rurouni Kenshin' TV Anime Unveils Cast, Staff, 2023 Premiere</title>
      <description>The Aniplex Online Fest 2022 event unveiled the main cast, staff, a character visual (pictured), and first promotional video for the new television anime adaptation of Nobuhiro Watsuki&#039;s Rurouni Kenshin: Meiji Kenkaku Romantan (Rurouni Kenshin: Meiji Swordsman Romantic Story) manga on Saturday. The new anime series will premiere on Fuji TV&#039;s noitaminA programming block in 2023. Souma Saitou (Yuukoku no Moriarty) and Rie Takahashi (Re:Zero kara Hajimeru Isekai Seikatsu) are starring as...</description>
      <media:thumbnail>https://cdn.myanimelist.net/s/common/uploaded_files/1663995793-1143f1e9dc9d1c3ed8c083793f9727c8.jpeg</media:thumbnail>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Sep 2022 22:04:50 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://myanimelist.net/news/67542620?_location=rss</link>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
